Guide to the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), Pittsburgh Branch Records, 1940-1974 AIS.1964.38
ULS Archives & Special Collections
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), Pittsburgh Branch Records
1940-1974
ULS Archives & Special Collections
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Pittsburgh Branch
AIS.1964.38
32.5 Linear Feet (61 boxes)
The Records of the NAACP Pittsburgh Branch consist of an extensive collection of correspondence, minutes, local headquarters activities, chapter records, membership campaigns, bills and receipts, reports, pamphlets and other miscellaneous information.
History
The NAACP, National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, is the oldest, largest and strongest civil rights organization in the United States. The NAACP was created in 1909 with the merging of the Niagara Movement, a group of young African-Americans led by W.E.B. Du Bois, and a group of concerned white citizens. The principal objective of the NAACP is to ensure the political, educational, social and economic equality of minority group citizens of the United States.
The Records of the Pittsburgh Branch of the NAACP were maintained from the early 1940's while the Honorable Homer S. Brown served as President. The records of the organization document various forms of racism in Pittsburgh as well as cases emerging across the nation. The Pittsburgh Branch participated in fund raising to provide for legal defense in civil rights cases. A recurring problem in the Pittsburgh area was the discrimination at public swimming pools. The NAACP kept files about the Highland Park Swimming Pool,and both the Kennywood and West View Park pools. The Branch eventually formed the NAACP Active Swimming Pool Committee to protect the right of every citizen to have admission without fear of segregation to public swimming pools in Pittsburgh.
The Pittsburgh Branch was active in addressing the concerns of its members by petitioning for anti-discrimination laws, federal aid for education, desegregation, housing discrimination programs, and fair employment practices in order to ensure the basic rights of minorities. Voter registration and membership campaigns are important components of the NAACP's work. By gathering a base of voters committed to Civil Rights the organization supported their candidates into elected positions.
Scope and Content Notes
The Records of the NAACP, Pittsburgh Branch, consist of correspondence, reports of chapter to national headquarters; minutes of Executive Board meetings, reports of chapter's activities, chapter programs on: segregation in labor and industry, employment, education, housing, and public accommodations; membership campaigns, cards, and record books; financial statements, paid bills, and receipt books. The records also include public relations information, and miscellaneous pamphlets.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the NAACP, Pittsburgh Branch, September 1, 1964, September 19, 1968, 1974.
Previous Citations
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Pittsburgh Branch Records, 1964-1966, 1974, AIS.1964.38, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Pittsburgh Branch Records, 1964-1966, 1974, AIS.1964.38, Archives Services Center, University of Pittsburgh
African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies and clubs; Associations; Social action; African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Social conditions -- to 1964.; African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Segregation.; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Pittsburgh Branch
- 1944
  - Pittsburgh Officers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Membership ledger, undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
- 1945
  - Local Officers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pennsylvania Branches and Officers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Membership Campaigns, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Forms and letters regarding memberships and contributions, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Membership campaigns, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Membership report blanks, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous committee reports, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - FEPC, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Youth Council, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1946
  - Incoming correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership report blanks, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Isaac Woodward Mass Meeting, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - News releases, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 1947
  - Correspondence and other items, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Membership Campaigns, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Membership report blanks, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 1948
  - Incoming correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Membership campaign, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
  - Membership report blanks, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Highland Park Swimming Pool, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous complaints, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ingram Defense Fund, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1949
  - Election of officers, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and other items, March-May 1949 (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
  - Membership campaign, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Membership Campaign, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Suggested calendar of activities for NAACP branches, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 1950
  - Incoming correspondence, March - May 1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May 1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Membership campaign, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Membership report blanks, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Swimming pool, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Supply receipts, April - May 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 1951
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Membership report blanks, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Paid bills, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
- 1952
  - Incoming correspondence, January-August 1952 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Outgoing correspondence, September-April 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, May-December 1952 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Membership campaign, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Form letters, voters registration, fund raising, membership, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Membership report blanks, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Financial statements, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Survey Report of Opinions of Members of the Pittsburgh Branch", 1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - List of accomplishments for the year, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Complaint cases, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Swimming pools, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - Migrant labor, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Fair Employment Practice, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Veterans folder, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - News releases, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 43rd Annual Convention, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ballots, election of officers, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Girl Friends Inc., 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- 1953
  - Incoming correspondence, January-December 1953 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, January-December 1953 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - Membership campaign, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Financial statements, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Form Letters, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Annual report of the executive secretary, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Committee to end discrimination in Places of Public Accommodation, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Complaint cases, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - State Legislative, 1953-1956 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Report of job applications, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National office news releases, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
- 1954
  - Incoming correspondence, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing correspondence, January - December 1954 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, January - December 1954 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Membership campaign, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Financial reports, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Form letters, miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Labor and industry, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Swimming pool life guards, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Legal Redress Committee, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Segregated proms at Westinghouse High School-MISSING, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Complaint cases, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - F.E.P.C. Review: Events in Pittsburgh Fair Employment Practices, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Spaulding Legal Defense Fund, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Human Rights Dinner, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Concert, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- 1955
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Executive Committee reports and financial statements, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Housing, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - F.E.P.C., 1955-1958 (Box 12, Folder 7-10)
  - Membership report blanks, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - List of clubs and organizations, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Public Accommodations Committee, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Discrimination in Braddock, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Complaint cases, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Civic Unity Council, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Federal Aid to School Construction Bill, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Education folder, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mississippi Mass Meeting, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Human Rights Dinner, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Benefit concert, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Women's Auxiliary, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Youth Council, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- 1956
  - Incoming correspondence, January-December 1956 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - Outgoing correspondence, January-May 1956 (Box 14, Folder 5-7)
  - Executive board, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Financial statements, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Membership campaign, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - Edward Shelton, personal file, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Gilmore Wade, personal file, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination complaint cases, 1956-1958 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Housing, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Human Rights Dinner, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
  - Contributions to the NAACP Alabama Legal Defense Fund, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Federal Aid to School Construction Bill, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - News Releases, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Radio Broadcasts, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Council for Intercultural Education, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Communication on Human Relations, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and conventions material, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Pray and Pay Rally" in support of the Montgomery Bus Boycott, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Youth Council, 1956-1959 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
  - Clubs and organizations, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clubs and organizations, 1956, 1957-1959 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Ronald Dye court martial proceedings, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
- 1957
  - Incoming correspondence, January-December 1957 (Box 18, Folder 3-6)
  - National office correspondence, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, January-December 1957 (Box 18, Folder 8-10)
  - Unlabeled Volume, 1957 (Box 19, Volume 1)
  - Executive board, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Financial statements, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Membership campaigns, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
  - Life memberships, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Public accommodations, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Labor and industry, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
  - Complaint of employment discrimination against Veterans Hospital, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Education folder, 1957-1958 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  - Human Relations Commission, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Human Rights Dinner, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
  - News releases from the national office, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 7-9)
  - News items and circulars, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Health and Welfare Federation, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Mental Health Society of Allegheny County, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Florence Ligon complaint case, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Public relations, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Scholarships, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- 1958
  - Incoming correspondence, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 4-8)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence with Lucille Black, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report of the President, Pittsburgh Chapter, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Financial statements, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Membership campaign, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Fair housing, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
  - Labor and Industry Committee, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
  - Human Relations Commission, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Human Rights Dinner, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
  - NAACP College Chapter, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Church folder, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Homestead Community Center, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Women's Auxiliary, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and conventions, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
  - News releases and clippings, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
  - Paid bills, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 10-12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- 1959
  - Incoming correspondence, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 2-7)
  - Incoming correspondence, National Office, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence with Pennsylvania Department of Labor and Industry, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with membership secretary of the National Office, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence in regards to the "Larry Steele Show", 1959 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Finance Committee, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
  - Monthly reports, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Derrick Bell, personal file, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Leroy Norris, personal file, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Weekly financial reports, January - December 1959 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
  - Membership campaign, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 4-7)
  - Voter registration campaign, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - State Fair Housing Bill, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Statements made before the committee on Law and Order of the State Legislature, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Fair Employment Practices Commission, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Employment and employment practices, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Persons seeking employment, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Public Accommodations Committee, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Pittsburgh Commission on Human Rights, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Health and Welfare Association of Allegheny County, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Equal Rights Council, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Rosedale Beach Pool, discrimination case, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous complaint cases, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Student Councils, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - 11th Annual Conference of the National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Pennsylvania State Conference Officers and Executive Board, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia car raffle, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Polio clinics, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Black Muslims, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - 50th Anniversary Program of the Pittsburgh Branch, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 9-11)
  - "Porgy and Bess" premiere, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Items from the Washington Bureau, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 14-16)
  - Conferences and conventions, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 17-18)
  - State conferences, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Popularity contest, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
  - New releases, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 5-7)
  - Clippings, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Paid bills, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 11)
- 1960
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Marion B Jordan, personal file, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Membership campaign, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 4-8)
  - Ballots, 1960 election of officers (Box 30, Folder 9-10)
  - NAACP committees, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Complaint cases, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Statement of policy, 51st Annual Convention of the NAACP, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Day Book, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Campaign Kit for Membership Chairman, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Membership campaign, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - Miscellaneous financial reports, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Fair Housing, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 5-7)
  - Miscellaneous discrimination cases, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Fair employment, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Derrick Bell, Executive Secretary, Pittsburgh Branch, biographic data, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - List of organizations, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Cartoons, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- 1948-1969
  - The Crisis incomplete holdings, 1952-1960 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Building Today for Tomorrow in Our Neighborhood (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Fellowship, July, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Social Action in the Local Church (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Education in a Transition Community (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Officer's Report to IUE-CIO, 1952, October 6-10 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Brotherhood Week: What Can Secondary Schools Do? (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Southern School News, July 1958-May 1959 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Southern School News, June 1959-June 1960 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Conference resolutions, annual conventions and annual reports (Box 33, Folder 3)
- 1953-1960
  - Milwaukee Commission on Human Rights Annual Report, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Governor's Commission on Industrial Race Relations, February 1953 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Report of Community Tensions in Central North Side and Manchester, June 1957 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Human Relations Review, 1956-1957, incomplete holdings (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - The Aged in Allegheny County: a plan for services, June 1960 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - "Among Ourselves" a play by Janet Roos (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania Fair Employment Practice Commission Annual Reports, 1955-1960 (Box 33, Folder 10)
- 1947-1961
  - Treasurer's Warrant Book, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Receipt books, 1959-1961 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Membership records and campaigns, 1947, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Membership records and campaigns, 1948, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 4)
- 1959-1960
  - Allegheny Council on Civil Rights, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Branch Directory, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Marion B. Jordan, biographic material, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Bills, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Churches, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Community Magazine, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Complaints, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
  - Complaint cases, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Commission on Human Relations, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Conferences and conventions, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Incoming contributions, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Outgoing contributions, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Incoming correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 15-17)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence from National Office, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to National Office, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Council of Churches, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Clubs and organizations, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 7)
- 1960
  - Educational, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Employment, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 10-11)
  - Executive Committee Meeting and Financial Report, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - F.E.P.C., 1960 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Finance Committee, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Health and Welfare, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Housing, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Community Relations Council, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Legislation, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Life Membership, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 19-20)
  - Membership Campaign, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Memorandums, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Monthly Reports, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - News Items, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - News Releases - Courier, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - News Releases - National, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 9-10)
  - Paid Bills, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Louise Payne, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Personnel Practices, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - Persons Seeking Employment, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - The Presbyterian, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Program File, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - President's Miscellaneous File, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - News Releases, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Renewal Campaign, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - State Conference, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Southern School News - Incomplete Holdings, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Voter Registration, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Weekly Reports, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Women's Auxiliary, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Youth Council, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Washington Bureau, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- 1960-1961
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1960-1961 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Material, 1960-1961 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Branch Directory, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Cases and Complaints, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Churches, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Clubs and Organizations, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Complaints, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Commission on Human Relations, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
  - Conferences and Conventions, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Contributions - Incoming, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Contributions - Outgoing, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 10)